[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c31e", "question": "What is the name of Google's mobile operating system?", "answer": "Android", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2a2", "question": "Which general's father led the investigation of the Lindbergh baby kidnapping?", "answer": "Norman Schwarzkopf", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd34", "question": "What large US city calls its newspaper the Bee?", "answer": "Sacramento", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397d7", "question": "Meg Ryan and Tom Hanks appeared together for the first time in which movie?", "answer": "Joe Versus the Volcano", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b928", "question": "What color is the smoke announcing the election of a new pope?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea34acff048f679a45aaf9", "question": "What unit of measure is used to quantify radioactive element activity?", "answer": "Becqueral", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e2b", "question": "Who is Jamie Lee Curtis' mother?", "answer": "Janet Leigh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b943364247bf200fb88a", "question": "Who popularized the song \"A Boy Named Sue\" in 1969?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf94", "question": "What does an onychophagist do?", "answer": "Bite their nails", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec1", "question": "During which battle did the charge of the Light Brigade take place?", "answer": "Balaclava", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c704", "question": "What is the only chemical element whose name is only three letters long?", "answer": "Tin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b89b", "question": "How many points do you score for a bullseye in archery?", "answer": "10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59523bff736d4be723796b33", "question": "On what day does Canada celebrate its birthday?", "answer": "July 1", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d3f", "question": "What TV show, besides \"Green Acres\", is set in the town of Hooterville?", "answer": "Petticoat Junction", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6b7", "question": "The Columbia River flows into what body of water?", "answer": "Pacific Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe64146ae7e414034b5aeaa", "question": "Approximately how long did the gunfight at the O.K Corral in Tombstone, Arizona last?", "answer": "Thirty seconds", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffe4ba247818f5674af01b2", "question": "From which novel is this quote \"I am no bird; and no net ensnares me; I am a free human being with an independent will.\"?", "answer": "\"Jane Eyre\" (Jane Eyre famously says this to Mr. Rochester, whom she loves, but claims she is still capable of leaving.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c04b", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of the Bahamas?", "answer": "American flamingo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909d209bb53d1af65886505", "question": "Who played the role of the Grinch in the 2000 film \"How the Grinch Stole Christmas\"?", "answer": "Jim Carrey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339483", "question": "What powers Monstropolis in the movie \"Monsters, Inc.\"?", "answer": "Screams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f9a", "question": "What book was the film \"Three Days Of The Condor\" based on?", "answer": "Six Days Of The Condor", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df4", "question": "In 1853, what author founded a successful daily journal called \"Le Mousquetaire\"?", "answer": "Alexandre Dumas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ded077ea2747c8aff16d28", "question": "Ireland's River Shannon flows into which ocean?", "answer": "Atlantic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339791", "question": "What KISS star sported the longest tongue in rock?", "answer": "Gene Simmons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa6f06ce05a3942286ecd", "question": "In the film \"Fargo\", Jerry Lundegaard was captured by the police in what city?", "answer": "Bismarck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cdd10e347d002c297e4ec", "question": "How was the Greek city of Troy penetrated?", "answer": "Using a wooden horse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c97", "question": "What playwright wrote \"Death of a Salesman\"?", "answer": "Arthur Miller", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa3acfc73aa70ea0b70ae1", "question": "What is the highest waterfall in Europe?", "answer": "The\u00a0Krimml Waterfalls", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff66bd552a821ff76ae8b10", "question": "Which was the last state in the United States that declared Christmas a legal holiday?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c90d22852800b05cac20f13", "question": "What are the names of the 5 Space Shuttle Orbiters used by NASA on manned spaceflight missions?", "answer": "Columbia, Challenger, Discovery, Atlantis, Endeavour", "category": "science"}, {"id": "594a62a32ebb971c1417fb91", "question": "What fish was the subject of a dispute between Spain and Canada from 1994 to 1996?", "answer": "Turbot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3ab", "question": "What postal code has Canada Post assigned to Santa Claus's residence at the North Pole?", "answer": "H0H 0H0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a5da20565ad31a57c7d2", "question": "What image was on the world's first jigsaw puzzle?", "answer": "A map", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ae", "question": "The first spin-off of C.S.I., starting in 2002, was set in what city?", "answer": "Miami", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d3c", "question": "What \"Animal House\" actor made his show-biz debut as the voice of TV's Jonny Quest?", "answer": "Tim Matheson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aab", "question": "Who said, \"Do give books - religious or otherwise - for Christmas\"?", "answer": "Lenore Hershey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f748ea9e54d890926f6f9", "question": "In California, you can\u2019t legally buy a mousetrap without having what?", "answer": "Hunting license", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339674", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who is Apu married to?", "answer": "Manjula", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a979661d1b4d384d5d686", "question": "In the world of tennis, who was the first to win all four Grand Slams in the same year?", "answer": "Don Budge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3e91738e4e5d4832e630e", "question": "In the Bible in the book of Job, who begins the first discourse to Job?", "answer": "Eliphaz", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe69ec220565ad31a57c787", "question": "Which First Lady was the first to hold a job after marriage?", "answer": "Abigail Powers Fillmore", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8f5", "question": "What US state's civil law is most closely based on the Napoleonic Code?", "answer": "Louisiana's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7b8", "question": "What is measured in Millibars?", "answer": "Pressure", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c20c877e98cb97778984", "question": "Where can you find \"Aphrodite's Rock\"?", "answer": "Cyprus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e90ff6dd7247dfc0fa0030a", "question": "Under what name was \"Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone\" published in the US?", "answer": "Harry Potter and the Sorcerer's Stone", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59636c30967692ea851899a8", "question": "Which \"Committee of Five\" member was the 2nd President of the United States?", "answer": "John Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe737f9eec85e375820b25e", "question": "What U.S. state produces the greatest number of Christmas trees, more specifically Douglas fir?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b699175e762b54eb9be9419", "question": "What decade saw the popularization of the Charleston dance?", "answer": "The 1920s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa5e673838c5c8a417f2c", "question": "The aardvark is native to which continent?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9053601dd7bf43be5e87a", "question": "What does \"In vino veritas\" translate into?", "answer": "In wine is truth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5b5", "question": "What was the original intended use for the RC car prior to being a toy?", "answer": "War", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4b0a49076251badbeac0", "question": "What was Dwight D. Eisenhower's major campaign slogan during the 1952 presidential election?", "answer": "\"I like Ike\" -- Ike was Eisenhower's nickname.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339df7", "question": "What is the subject of Claude Lanzmann's award-winning nine-hour film \"Shoah\"?", "answer": "The Holocaust", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba46", "question": "What Philadelphia building appears on the back of the US $100 bill?", "answer": "Independence Hall", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c6c1fbde8045e48466b9", "question": "Which naturally occurring element is heaviest by atomic weight?", "answer": "Uranium -- At present, ununoctium is the heaviest but it's man-made, and so disqualified as a \"naturally\" occurring element.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd93", "question": "Who merged with the struggling Cleveland Barons in 1978?", "answer": "The Minnesota North Stars", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ccf7b08b37b32637bdc44c3", "question": "In what year was the first opera created?", "answer": "1597", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecdb69ec223966ae8f88f5", "question": "The script for what movie was written during shooting breaks on the set of \"Raiders of the Lost Ark\"?", "answer": "E.T.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae6", "question": "How many strikes in a row earns you a perfect game in regular 10\u00ad pin bowling?", "answer": "12", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c49d", "question": "Self-rising flour contains what crucial ingredient?", "answer": "Baking powder", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c3", "question": "What country covers an entire continent?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601737ef44491cbd7c5a1790", "question": "During World War II, prisoners wearing a green triangle in a concentration camp signified the prisoners were what?", "answer": "Criminals or convicts (often working as kapos)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339402", "question": "Which actor played the role of the Grinch in the 2000 movie \"How the Grinch Stole Christmas\"?", "answer": "Jim Carrey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133addc", "question": "Joan of Arc won several victories for France in which European war?", "answer": "Hundred Year's War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9bab4364247bf200fb89b", "question": "Tribology is the study of what?", "answer": "Friction, lubrication and wear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea4653ff048f679a45aba1", "question": "What kind of muscle contraction is also referred to as \"static tension\"?", "answer": "Isometric", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a03b", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", which one of Peter's friends married Peter's maid, Joan, for a week?", "answer": "Quagmire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3f5", "question": "What age preceded the Iron Age?", "answer": "The Bronze Age", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6008dd6df4f3bc4a292f8621", "question": "Who was president the first time the U.S. Congress voted to declare war?", "answer": "James Madison (On 1 June 1812, he sent a message to Congress recounting U.S. grievances against Great Britain.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0e4", "question": "In the 1990s, what was the name Operation Desert Storm known as before it escalated to a full-fledged siege?", "answer": "Desert Shield", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf4d", "question": "What is the fear of things to the left or left-handed known as?", "answer": "Sinistrophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acb7", "question": "How many main islands make up the state of Hawaii?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea461dff048f679a45ab9e", "question": "What is the Hawaiian name for yellow fin tuna?", "answer": "Ahi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394f8", "question": "Who hosted \"The Daily Show\" before Jon Stewart?", "answer": "Craig Kilborn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d98", "question": "What longtime London Symphony Orchestra conductor is also Woody Allen's father-in-law?", "answer": "Andre Previn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b184", "question": "What year was US President Ronald Reagan born?", "answer": "1911", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a127", "question": "Who said \"I always thought losing my virginity was a career move\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7e3", "question": "When is the optical phenomenon called a \"green flash\" or \"green ray\" visible?", "answer": "Sunrise or sunset", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7736ceec85e375820b307", "question": "Which U.S. state is closest to the Tropic of Cancer?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6a1", "question": "Clams and snails are part of what phylum or biological classification?", "answer": "Mollusks", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a6", "question": "What is the alternative name for the \"Mona Lisa\"?", "answer": "La Gioconda", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015ee47fe83fe1f2a824c08", "question": "What does parsley dipped in salt water on the Seder plate represent?", "answer": "Tears and pain of the Jewish slaves", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f14", "question": "What author created Wonderland?", "answer": "Lewis Carroll", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0b9", "question": "Who tore up a picture of the Pope on US television in 1992?", "answer": "Sinead O'Connor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ac", "question": "What is Homer Simpson's middle initial?", "answer": "J", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c416", "question": "How many horns did a triceratops have?", "answer": "Three", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbc5", "question": "How long is a fortnight?", "answer": "Two weeks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a743", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Old Line State\"?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa38e9c73aa70ea0b70ad6", "question": "How many U.S. states are named after a President?", "answer": "One (Washington is named after George Washington, the first U.S. president.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe9f07aff048f679a45aa9d", "question": "Pteromerhanophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Flying", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b722", "question": "What was used as the first Christmas collection kettle by the Salvation Army?", "answer": "A large crabpot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e49", "question": "What did Ignatz Mouse enjoy throwing at Krazy Kat's head?", "answer": "A brick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c1", "question": "What CEO bounced back after being fired by Henry Ford II in 1978?", "answer": "Lee Iacocca", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339651", "question": "What kind of animal is the title character in the 1998 movie \"Paulie\"?", "answer": "Parrot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3cefff048f679a45ab44", "question": "Which animal can cause a tularemia infection in humans while being skinned for cooking purposes?", "answer": "Rabbits", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6012150063c99d48cd169ae5", "question": "Einstein won the 1921 Nobel Prize for Physics for explaining what?", "answer": "Photoelectric effect -- However, that did not stop him from giving a lecture\u00a0on relativity in his acceptance speech.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a57d", "question": "Kodiak Island is the largest island in which US state?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c3e", "question": "Who wrote the children's classic \"Green Eggs and Ham\"?", "answer": "Dr. Seuss", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c7d", "question": "Who is the creator of the \"Desperate Housewives\" TV series?", "answer": "Marc Cherry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c932", "question": "What has superseded Newtonian mechanics of the atomic scale?", "answer": "Quantum mechanics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c5b", "question": "In what novel would you find the character known as the Artful Dodger?", "answer": "Oliver Twist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a838", "question": "What Ivy League university is located in Ithaca, NY?", "answer": "Cornell", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd7", "question": "What kind of cheese is most commonly sold in the US as processed \"string cheese\"?", "answer": "Mozzarella", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339321", "question": "In the movie \"Hangover\", what name did Alan use to refer to his circle of friends?", "answer": "The wolf pack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5989acf0cb8751d53e7d760d", "question": "What is the collective noun for a group of ruffs?", "answer": "A hill", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6010cb0d0775fa611bce6802", "question": "The last leader of the Soviet Union, Mikhail Gorbachev, was in what restaurant commercial?", "answer": "Pizza Hut", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339331", "question": "What western drama series told the story of Pat Garrett and Billy the Kid?", "answer": "The Tall Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51aebff04d658268c930a", "question": "Who kept Odysseus trapped on a remote island for seven years?", "answer": "Along his journey in \"The Odyssey\" Odysseus became trapped on the island of Ogygia as a prisoner of the goddess-nymph Calypso.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4d9", "question": "What fruit comes in Bing and Rainier variety?", "answer": "Cherries", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8efe901dd7bf43be5e7f6", "question": "What is the official name for a blob of toothpaste on a toothbrush?", "answer": "Nurdle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e57", "question": "What word for a series of dots is a top secret code word in the Bond film \"Casino Royale\"?", "answer": "Ellipsis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133952b", "question": "What rock musician was known as \"The Lizard King\"?", "answer": "Jim Morrison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af0d", "question": "What nickname was given to General Thomas J. Jackson during the Civil War?", "answer": "\"Stonewall\" Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d2672596a59cbdfbd38e", "question": "What is the only landlocked country in Southeast Asia?", "answer": "Laos", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba83", "question": "Where did Saints quarterback Drew Brees play college football?", "answer": "Purdue University", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394fb", "question": "In the movie \"300\", how many of the 300 Spartan warriors survive?", "answer": "One", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338967", "question": "Who spent months rehearsing for \"My Fair Lady\" then had most of her singing dubbed by Marni Nixon?", "answer": "Audrey Hepburn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a653", "question": "Which US state is nickname the \"Palmetto State\"?", "answer": "South Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b658", "question": "What baseball great was nicknamed the Iron Man?", "answer": "Cal Ripken Jr.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beb3", "question": "Which cuisine gave us kimchi and bulgogi?", "answer": "Korean", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4bff49076251badbeacb", "question": "Which U.S. President had the most children?", "answer": "John Tyler -- The 10th president had 16 children \u2014 15 with his two wives and one born out of wedlock.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8ab2b01dd7bf43be5e764", "question": "What does the term \"contrived patina\" mean?", "answer": "A weathered-looking surface", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abfd", "question": "The Mus\u00e9e d'Orsay in Paris was originally what?", "answer": "Railway Station", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab6a", "question": "What was Banlgadesh formerly known as until its independence?", "answer": "East Pakistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c87d", "question": "What masculine first name is also the zoological term for \"fish semen\"?", "answer": "Milt", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd96c3823c87fd04dd15e21", "question": "What Jelly Belly flavor was created for Ronald Reagan's inauguration?", "answer": "Blueberry", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b409", "question": "What year did the US issue a patent on the production of margarine?", "answer": "1871", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8aa7401dd7bf43be5e75b", "question": "What is the marketing term for the Monday after Thanksgiving day in the USA?", "answer": "Cyber Monday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af91", "question": "Who was assassinated by Leon Czolgosz?", "answer": "President William McKinley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339974", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Lenny's real full name?", "answer": "Lenford Leonard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7e78fb24f84e0b9f9ffba", "question": "By what name was Milwaukee's Pettit National Ice Center known as until 1991?", "answer": "Wisconsin Olympic Ice Rink", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b38d", "question": "Which famous artist designed the Chupa Chups logo in 1969?", "answer": "Salvador Dali", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394bb", "question": "Who played the role of Lamont Sanford in the TV show \"Sanford and Son\"?", "answer": "Desmond Wilson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c26b", "question": "What does a man suffering from \"diphallic terata\" have?", "answer": "Two penises", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a15e", "question": "What is the occupation of Mary Poppins?", "answer": "Nanny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb3f765ff7d326b622a82", "question": "Where was Budweiser first brewed in the US?", "answer": "St. Louis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c738", "question": "Dry Ice is the solid form of what chemical compound?", "answer": "Carbon dioxide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ae", "question": "Who was the first African-American to win an Academy Award for an acting role?", "answer": "Hattie McDaniel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fb5", "question": "In his Snake Plissken movies, what kind of snake is Kurt Russell's stomach tattoo?", "answer": "Cobra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ccf7bb0b37b32637bdc44c6", "question": "In what year was the language learning site/app Duolingo launched?", "answer": "2011", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8ab3d01dd7bf43be5e765", "question": "The Danish concept \"hygge\", often used in Scandinavian design, means what?", "answer": "Coziness and comfort", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c5d", "question": "Who was the Roman God of Love?", "answer": "Cupid", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393b9", "question": "What actor plays the role of Evan Treborn in the movie \"The Butterfly Effect\"?", "answer": "Ashton Kucher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac01", "question": "The Plains of Abraham is in which Canadian province?", "answer": "Quebec", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a429", "question": "What lake is the world's deepest lake?", "answer": "Lake Baikal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f9b753364247bf200fb871", "question": "Which chemical element has the atomic number of 1?", "answer": "Hydrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c011", "question": "Sakhmet was the Egyptian god of what?", "answer": "War and healing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c836fbde8045e48466d3", "question": "Where is the observatory where Percival Lowell first theorized the existence of Pluto?", "answer": "Flagstaff, Arizona", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a29b", "question": "Which English director founded the Theatre Workshop?", "answer": "Joan Littlewood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133949e", "question": "Who wrote the novel the miniseries \"Shogun\" was based on?", "answer": "James Clavell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa5707c73aa70ea0b70b2f", "question": "Which U.S. town is home to the world's largest rose bush?", "answer": "Tombstone, Arizona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a8", "question": "In 1990 Jennifer Aniston appeared in what short-lived TV show adapted from a popular movie?", "answer": "Ferris Bueller", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600241934be4723ccac22179", "question": "In the Harry Potter books, what name is given to non-magicians?", "answer": "Muggles", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f10401dd7bf43be5e802", "question": "What common household item inspired the soles of Nike's first running shoes?", "answer": "Waffle iron", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1b3", "question": "Who read the poem \"On the Pulse of Morning\" at Bill Clinton's first inauguration?", "answer": "Maya Angelou", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c09", "question": "What year was Anna Nicole Smith selected as a Playboy Playmate of the Year?", "answer": "1993", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c860877e98cb977789e3", "question": "Which city is the only capital located on the Rhine River?", "answer": "Vaduz, Liechtenstein", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b642", "question": "What type of tea is flavored with oil from the bergamot orange?", "answer": "Earl Grey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6aa8820565ad31a57c81a", "question": "In which German city did Joseph Stalin, Winston Churchill and President Franklin D Roosevelt meet in 1945?", "answer": "Potsdam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c092", "question": "Who invented the Gatling gun?", "answer": "Richard Jordan Gatling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3b3", "question": "What occurs when the Sun and the Moon are in conjunction as viewed from Earth?", "answer": "A solar eclipse", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5cd40e06685cf15b733e9896", "question": "In fencing what is the name of the action when two fencers make physical contact with any part of their bodies (or hilts)?", "answer": "Corps-a-corps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff7c0962b316f4693fb6797", "question": "What app, a monster hit in 2016, has been credited with teaching Americans the metric system?", "answer": "Pok\u00e9mon GO", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afaf", "question": "In 1907, what did the volunteer force \"The Yeomanry\" become known as?", "answer": "British Territorial Army", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfa2", "question": "What are wrapped in bacon to make the dish \"Angels on Horseback\"?", "answer": "Oysters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a072", "question": "What planet did Alf come from?", "answer": "Melmac", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f11", "question": "Who starred as the Doctor in the TV show \"Dr. Who\" from 1963 to 1966?", "answer": "William Hartnell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af69", "question": "During what war did thousands of Americans invade the shores of Normandy?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd6a3346c0f9723ab15cb4b", "question": "What was Ronald Reagan\u2019s Secret Service code name?", "answer": "Rawhide", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cada", "question": "What is the name of the telescope that was launched into orbit in 1990?\u00a0", "answer": "Hubble\u00a0Space Telescope", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd96dda23c87fd04dd15e30", "question": "Who was the first U.S. Vice President to resign?", "answer": "John C. Calhoun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389c4", "question": "What is Mr. Sowerberry's job in Oliver Twist?", "answer": "Undertaker", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4b6cf06d333868d34d6f5", "question": "Who assumed power as Prime Minister of Libya in 1970?", "answer": "Muammar Al-Gaddafi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e2", "question": "What birthday does Bridget celebrate in the course of the book \"Bridget Jones's Diary\"?", "answer": "33rd", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdc0d0e469bb8041d07a057", "question": "What does \"Mylo\" mean in \"Sony Mylo\"?", "answer": "My life online", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2b4", "question": "The VIC-20 and PET were personal computers manufactured by which company?", "answer": "Commodore International, Ltd.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdbf", "question": "What is traditionally the main fruit ingredient in a guacamole?", "answer": "Avocadoes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cd753e347d002c297e4c1", "question": "What is the only continent without native reptiles and snakes?", "answer": "Antarctica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff25a6431a458464a93c471", "question": "What group of animals is called a \"flink\"?", "answer": "A group of 12 or more cows", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c54a", "question": "What is most likely to occur when your diaphragm goes into spasms?", "answer": "Hiccups", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2cf562596a59cbdfbd36e", "question": "Who said, \u201cWhen the debate is lost, slander becomes the tool of the loser\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bd3", "question": "According to Greek mythology, what were Jason and the Argonauts searching for?", "answer": "The Golden Fleece", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fa2", "question": "A story of ones own life is referred to as what?", "answer": "Autobiography", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c70c", "question": "Something which is an \"emetic\" makes you do what?", "answer": "Vomit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bba1", "question": "What is the name for the fingers of a fork?", "answer": "Tines", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338959", "question": "What eye complaint is blamed for the reddish tone of some of Monet's paintings?", "answer": "Cataracts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a492", "question": "Which US city was once called New Amsterdam?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4edb206d333868d34d76f", "question": "Which language has the longest alphabet?", "answer": "Cambodian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa62a73838c5c8a417f2e", "question": "What is the fungi Hydnellum peckii, also known as?", "answer": "The bleeding tooth fungus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe938d96bd93ce3a4e5f688", "question": "What branch of science is concerned with the interaction between matter and electromagnetic radiation?", "answer": "Spectroscopy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdc2", "question": "Artist Bono shared Time's \"Man of the Year\" honors with what other man and his wife?", "answer": "Bill Gates", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec3", "question": "Who created the New Model Army?", "answer": "Oliver Cromwell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e5f10d3d274615ecf514537", "question": "What is another name for the \"Battle of Greasy Grass\"?", "answer": "The Battle of the Little Bighorn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b494", "question": "Which country hosted the 1900 Olympic Games?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab25", "question": "What is the capital of Madagascar?", "answer": "Antananarivo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ad7eba2b24f84e0b9f9ffdf", "question": "What town's name means \"House of Bread\" in Hebrew?", "answer": "Bethlehem", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab83", "question": "What year did Sierra Leone gain its independence from the UK?", "answer": "1961", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c033", "question": "What is the more common name for serigraphy?", "answer": "Screen printing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a5", "question": "In what century was the original Star Trek set?", "answer": "The 23rd century", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b305", "question": "How did Ponce de Leon, Claudius, and Tycho Brahe all die?", "answer": "They were poisoned", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597ddccb77980686f722d17a", "question": "What war saw the use of tanks in battle for first time?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be7", "question": "Who are the creators of the TV show \"Seinfeld\"?", "answer": "Larry David and Jerry Seinfeld", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4b4549076251badbeac1", "question": "Who was the first female U.S. Attorney General?", "answer": "Janet Reno -- She served as the attorney general for President Bill Clinton's entire presidency.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab92", "question": "What year did Cambodia gain its independence from France?", "answer": "1953", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c273", "question": "What is June's birthstone?", "answer": "Pearl", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dce", "question": "What two Rocky III costars won the final match of the very first WrestleMania?", "answer": "Mr. T and Hulk Hogan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc2f63fcee580c7f8fd1e5c", "question": "What was the leading cause of combatants' deaths during the American Civil War?", "answer": "Disease", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ed", "question": "What is the inflammation of the stomach and small intestine called?", "answer": "Gastroenteritis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f9e", "question": "What kind of bird is Wallace and Gromit's nemesis, Feathers McGraw?", "answer": "A penguin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a899b0e60d398dc9cf7a699", "question": "What is the first event in a Decathlon?", "answer": "100 metres", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a695", "question": "What is the official language of Guyana?", "answer": "English", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e5f0e89d274615ecf514535", "question": "The \"Sherwood Forest Plantation\", home to U.S. President John Tyler, is located in which U.S. state?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133977d", "question": "The Hobbit Samwise Gamgee was played by whom in Lord of the Rings?", "answer": "Sean Astin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad99", "question": "What decades was the Zodiac Killer active in the US?", "answer": "1960s and 1970s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c664", "question": "Phobos and Deimos are moons of what planet?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5937eaaf08d98002fdd633a6", "question": "Easter Island is part of which country?", "answer": "Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b8d", "question": "What love\u00adstruck Warner Brothers cartoon character often chased a black cat named Penelope?", "answer": "Pepe Le Pew", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c54c", "question": "\"Consumption\" was the former name of what disease?", "answer": "Tuberculosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b273", "question": "What nation saw thousands of forced disappearances during the \"Dirty War\" of 1976 to 1983?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a271", "question": "Who played the character of Paul Bratter in the 1967 film \"Barefoot in the Park\"?", "answer": "Robert Redford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a6", "question": "What movie starred Mel Gibson as William Wallace?", "answer": "Braveheart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a510", "question": "Which two independent states exist within Italy's borders?", "answer": "Vatican City and San Marino", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada7", "question": "How many years did the \"Great Plague of Milan\" last?", "answer": "Two", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59774255284458f1d785441f", "question": "Who played Secret Service Agent James West in The 1966-1968 television series \"The Wild, Wild, West\"?", "answer": "Robert Conrad", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b59d", "question": "Colors that are opposite each other on the color wheel are refered to as what?", "answer": "Complementary Colors", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f178223b8195c09b948d5c3", "question": "What mythical creature is St. George said to have slain?", "answer": "A dragon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a2", "question": "Who is known as Eminem?", "answer": "Marshall Mathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ea", "question": "What singer began his career fronting the bands of Harry James and Tommy Dorsey in the 1930\u2019s?", "answer": "Frank Sinatra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feddfef6ce05a3942286db4", "question": "What do you call an object a person uses to ensure they are not in someone else's dream in the movie \"Inception\"?", "answer": "A totem", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a5a", "question": "What is the name of the character that can be used in place of the word \"and\"?", "answer": "Ampersand", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feddc076ce05a3942286d97", "question": "What inspired the Grinch\u2019s green color?", "answer": "An ugly car", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3cf", "question": "The offspring of a male lion and a female tiger is known by what name?", "answer": "Liger", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc54", "question": "What is Marmite's marketing slogan?", "answer": "Love it or Hate it", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fedda986ce05a3942286d87", "question": "Who was the first player to win consecutive NBA MVP awards since Michael Jordan did it in 1991 and 1992?", "answer": "Tim Duncan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133975f", "question": "What two murderesses does Billy Flynn represent in Chicago?", "answer": "Velma Kelly and Roxie Hart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c90cf8052800b05cac20f0a", "question": "What is Sinology the study of?", "answer": "China", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9a0", "question": "What is -459.67 F also know as?", "answer": "Absolute Zero", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a146", "question": "Thomas Harris created what character?", "answer": "Hannibal Lecter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdfbe6d003d27d341092bce", "question": "Where is the world-famous Skytree tower located?", "answer": "Tokyo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133898a", "question": "Which Dickens character asked for more?", "answer": "Oliver Twist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febd9487e83c707845b2179", "question": "Who was the original \"Bozo the Clown\"?", "answer": "Vance \"Pinto\" Colvig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390b2", "question": "Who wrote the 1924 novel \"Beau Geste\"?", "answer": "P. C. Wren", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5a7", "question": "The city of Honolulu is located on what island?", "answer": "Oahu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d43", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"Alien 3\"?", "answer": "Sigourney Weaver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc776ec223966ae8f888d", "question": "In TV, what is Leonard Hofstader's middle name?", "answer": "Leakey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ec2b14943630d44e5be228c", "question": "Who started the vision for the long-established fashion for the Kentucky Derby races?", "answer": "Col. Meriwether Lewis Clark Jr.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062d85c9d816e292245c33", "question": "Who painted \"Sunday Afternoon on the Island of La Grande Jatte\"?", "answer": "It is the painting of Neo-Impressionist Georges Seurat, whose techniques using tiny brushstrokes became known as Pointillism.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd68", "question": "On what Jewish holiday is the \"Kol Nidre\" prayer recited?", "answer": "Yom Kippur", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c453", "question": "What part of the cinnamon tree becomes the spice?", "answer": "The bark", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a25eee56682715b82711cd2", "question": "Which building is typically considered to be the first skyscraper?", "answer": "The Home Insurance Building", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6a23b6c0f9723ab15cb40", "question": "How long was the Mayflower's journey to the New World?", "answer": "66 days", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9b8dc364247bf200fb884", "question": "Whose debut solo album was titled \"I Got Dem Ol' Kozmic Blues Again Mama!\"?", "answer": "Janis Joplin's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc3c", "question": "Approximately, how tall is the Leaning Tower of Pisa?", "answer": "56 m", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee7", "question": "Who was British Prime Minister on V-J day?", "answer": "Clement Attlee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe3e8ec38e4e5d4832e630d", "question": "What year was the battle of Bannockburn fought between the English and the Scots?", "answer": "1314", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd822e5d0de9af39e9d46ac", "question": "How many vice presidents did FDR have during his time in office?", "answer": "3", "category": "history"}]